

Kwangmin Kim

Data Scientist/ Data Analyst

Email: kmink3225@gmail.com Website: kmink3225.netlify.app

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kwangmin-kim-a5241b200/

ABOUT ME

Over 7 years of experience in data science with academic backgrounds in biochemistry, mathematics, and biostatistics and expertise in statistics and machine learning using open source tools such as R, Python, SQL, etc. I am interested in gaining a mathematical understanding of algorithms and modeling. I can communicate with non-experts using detailed objective facts obtained through data analysis. I aim to work in a planned, systematic way.

SKILLS

Data Scinece	Database	etc
R, Python	• SQlite	• Ubuntu, Powershell, Git/Github, Conda
• SAS	• Oracle-SQL	• Quarto, R markdown, Jupyter,

EXPERIENCE

2020.12 - Present

Seegene, Diagnosis IT General Research Institute, Data Science Team

Data Scientist / Data Analyst

- Algorithm DHF documentation and FDA verification & validation reporting.
- Diagnosis algorithms management and development.
- Device QC (Quality Control) algorithms management and development.
- Data analytic and statistical analysis.
- IP (Intellectual Property) planning and filed 7 patent inventions.

2019.05 - 2020.04

Columbia University Irving Medical Center, Taub Institute for Research on Alzheimer's Disease and the Aging Brain

Research Assistant

- Clinical data analytics: statistics, machine learning(ML), data mining, pathway analysis.
- Clinical data analysis pipeline construction for metabolomics.
- ML and statistics consulting to medical doctors, epidemiologists, and neurologists.

2018.12 - 2019.05

Columbia University Irving Medical Center,

Taub Institute for Research on Alzheimer's Disease and the Aging Brain Intern

- Researched and worked independently on a study comparing multiple machine learning algorithms to select an optimal classifier for metabolomics.
- Dimension reduction: variable selection and extraction for high dimensional data.

EDUCATION

2017.08 - 2019.05 2015.08 - 2017.05

2006.03 - 2012.02

- Columbia University in the City of New York, Biostatistics(MS), Department Head Award
- Baruch College, The City University of New York, Mathematics(BA)
- Kangwon National University, Biochemistry(BS), Summa Cum Laude, Full Scholarship

PROJECTS		AWARDS
2022.07 - present	 Algorithm DHF & FDA Verification & Validation Documentation Seegene, Diagnosis IT General Research Institute Diagnosis algorithm DHF planning and documentation. FDA verification & validation report documentation. Designed algorithm testing and constructed statistical analysis pipelines for algorithm verification as the product manager. Dynamic documentation using Quarto, R, and python. 	
2021.12 - 2022.07	 Platform Planning TF Seegene, Strategy Planning Office & In-house Patent Center Platform strategy planning and intellectual property planning. 5/16 inventions have been filed(the remaining 11 are ongoing). Database system, statistics, and ML knowledge consultation for executives, planners, and attorneys. 	Invention Compensation
2021.01 - 2021.09	 Data-Driven Diagnosis Algorithm Development Seegene, Strategy Planning Office & In-house Patent Center Planned and developed a data-driven signal processing algorithm. Reflected optical characteristics of diagnosis device. Reflected the unique technology of SG reagents. 	R&D Division Excellence Award Invention Compensation
2019.05 - 2020.04	 Diagnosis Device Quality Control (QC) Platform Construction Seegene, Diagnosis IT General Research Institute led all processes throughout the project as the product owner. Developed noise measurement algorithms. Collaborated with other departments to automate the two-stage QC process, visualize it, and reduce turnaround time by 11x. Classified device failures, human errors, and production line errors. 	
2018.12 - 2019.05	 Long Life Family Study (LLFS) Project Columbia University Irving Medical Center, Taub Institute Used statistics and ML to identify metabolic profiles significantly associated with dementia Analytics pipeline construction: missing value analysis, statistical analysis, ML classification, and pathway analysis Using data mining, a strong confounder was discovered that had not been found by the research institute for 8 months 	Department Head Award \$1,000 Stipend Job Offer
	 Analytic Project on Alzheimer's Disease and the Aging Brain Columbia University in the City of New York, Biostatistics Selected as one of the top 3 out of about 100 graduate students in the annual research competition for master's graduate students Comparative study of optimal ML methods for Alzheimer's Disease and the Aging Brain and metabolomics 	\$1,000 Stipend
2015.01 - 2015.06	 Using Tea Leaves, Heavy Metal Removal Algorithm Development The City University of New York, Mathematics Developed a mechanistic model that reflects the adsorption process of heavy metals into tea leaves using differential equation and non-linear least square algorithm 	